<resources>
    <string name="app_name">AdvisingV2</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="nav_header_title">UMD CS Advising</string>
    <string name="nav_header_subtitle">Your personal pocket advisor</string>
    <string name="nav_header_desc">Navigation header</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <string name="menu_resources">Resources</string>
    <string name="menu_gallery">Tools</string>
    <string name="menu_calendar">Advising Calendar</string>
    <string name="gpa_tab">GPA Calculator</string>
    <string name="course_requests">Course Request Form</string>
    <string name="four_year_plan">4 Year Plan</string>
    <string name="title_activity_utilities">UtilitiesActivity</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>


    <string name="undergrad_overview">At the Department of Computer Science, undergraduates are a priority. Here, you will meet 3,400 (and counting) of the nation\'s top computer science majors. This diverse group of students has interests ranging from systems to programming languages, from algorithms to design and from VR to Robotics. While you are an undergraduate here, you will study fundamentals in computing including programming languages and theory, which will help you later in a variety of courses we offer at the 400-level. After taking classes, perhaps doing research, participating in our honors program, or studying abroad, and completing internships, our students go on to some of the best graduate programs in the world or join start-ups, small and large tech companies, consulting firms, or government organizations.</string>
    <string name="undergrad_overview_title">Undergraduate Studies in Computer Science at the University of Maryland</string>

    <string name="contact_us">Contact Us!!</string>
    <string name="address">1st Floor, Brendan Iribe Center for Computer Science and Engineering</string>
    <string name="phone">(301) 405–2672</string>
    <string name="ugrad_email">ugrad@cs.umd.edu</string>
    <string name="hours">Monday - Friday 8:30 AM to 4:30 PM</string>
    <string name="socials">Facebook / Instagram / Twitter</string>

    <string name="advisors_title">Academic Advisors</string>
    <string name="contact_extra">Part of the Department of Computer Science Brendan Iribe Center for Computer Science and Engineering University of Maryland 8125 Paint Branch Drive College Park, MD 20742 (301) 405–2662</string>
    <string name="head_title">Heads of Staff</string>
    <string name="peers_title">Undergraduate Peer Advising Team</string>


    <string name="gpa_anticipated_header">Anticipated GPA Calculator</string>
    <string name="semester_gpa">Semester GPA:</string>
    <string name="cumulative_gpa">Cumulative GPA:</string>
    <string name="gpa_semester_help">To calculate your anticipated semester GPA:\n\t1. Press the "Add Course" Button to add a course to the calculator\n\t2. Enter the course name, number of credits, and grade.\n\t3. Press the ENTER button to add this course\n\t4. Repeat steps 1 through 3 for each course you are attempting</string>
    <string name="gpa_cumulative_help">To calculate your cumulative GPA:\n\t1. Enter your cumulative attempted credits (1–999)\n\t2. Enter your cumulative GPA between 0.0 and 4.0 </string>
    <string name="add_course">Add Course</string>
    <string name="semester_gpa_0_0">Semester GPA: 0.0</string>
    <string name="letter_grade_hint">+/- Letter Grade</string>
    <string name="course_name_hint">Course Name</string>
    <string name="calculate_cumulative">Calculate Cumulative</string>


    <string name="home">Dashboard</string>
    <string name="calendar">Upcoming</string>
    <string name="notifications">Inbox</string>
    <string name="tools">Settings</string>
    <string name="large_text">
        "Material is the metaphor.\n\n"

        "A material metaphor is the unifying theory of a rationalized space and a system of motion."
        "The material is grounded in tactile reality, inspired by the study of paper and ink, yet "
        "technologically advanced and open to imagination and magic.\n"
        "Surfaces and edges of the material provide visual cues that are grounded in reality. The "
        "use of familiar tactile attributes helps users quickly understand affordances. Yet the "
        "flexibility of the material creates new affordances that supercede those in the physical "
        "world, without breaking the rules of physics.\n"
        "The fundamentals of light, surface, and movement are key to conveying how objects move, "
        "interact, and exist in space and in relation to each other. Realistic lighting shows "
        "seams, divides space, and indicates moving parts.\n\n"

        "Bold, graphic, intentional.\n\n"

        "The foundational elements of print based design typography, grids, space, scale, color, "
        "and use of imagery guide visual treatments. These elements do far more than please the "
        "eye. They create hierarchy, meaning, and focus. Deliberate color choices, edge to edge "
        "imagery, large scale typography, and intentional white space create a bold and graphic "
        "interface that immerse the user in the experience.\n"
        "An emphasis on user actions makes core functionality immediately apparent and provides "
        "waypoints for the user.\n\n"

        "Motion provides meaning.\n\n"

        "Motion respects and reinforces the user as the prime mover. Primary user actions are "
        "inflection points that initiate motion, transforming the whole design.\n"
        "All action takes place in a single environment. Objects are presented to the user without "
        "breaking the continuity of experience even as they transform and reorganize.\n"
        "Motion is meaningful and appropriate, serving to focus attention and maintain continuity. "
        "Feedback is subtle yet clear. Transitions are efﬁcient yet coherent.\n\n"

        "3D world.\n\n"

        "The material environment is a 3D space, which means all objects have x, y, and z "
        "dimensions. The z-axis is perpendicularly aligned to the plane of the display, with the "
        "positive z-axis extending towards the viewer. Every sheet of material occupies a single "
        "position along the z-axis and has a standard 1dp thickness.\n"
        "On the web, the z-axis is used for layering and not for perspective. The 3D world is "
        "emulated by manipulating the y-axis.\n\n"

        "Light and shadow.\n\n"

        "Within the material environment, virtual lights illuminate the scene. Key lights create "
        "directional shadows, while ambient light creates soft shadows from all angles.\n"
        "Shadows in the material environment are cast by these two light sources. In Android "
        "development, shadows occur when light sources are blocked by sheets of material at "
        "various positions along the z-axis. On the web, shadows are depicted by manipulating the "
        "y-axis only. The following example shows the card with a height of 6dp.\n\n"

        "Resting elevation.\n\n"

        "All material objects, regardless of size, have a resting elevation, or default elevation "
        "that does not change. If an object changes elevation, it should return to its resting "
        "elevation as soon as possible.\n\n"

        "Component elevations.\n\n"

        "The resting elevation for a component type is consistent across apps (e.g., FAB elevation "
        "does not vary from 6dp in one app to 16dp in another app).\n"
        "Components may have different resting elevations across platforms, depending on the depth "
        "of the environment (e.g., TV has a greater depth than mobile or desktop).\n\n"

        "Responsive elevation and dynamic elevation offsets.\n\n"

        "Some component types have responsive elevation, meaning they change elevation in response "
        "to user input (e.g., normal, focused, and pressed) or system events. These elevation "
        "changes are consistently implemented using dynamic elevation offsets.\n"
        "Dynamic elevation offsets are the goal elevation that a component moves towards, relative "
        "to the component’s resting state. They ensure that elevation changes are consistent "
        "across actions and component types. For example, all components that lift on press have "
        "the same elevation change relative to their resting elevation.\n"
        "Once the input event is completed or cancelled, the component will return to its resting "
        "elevation.\n\n"

        "Avoiding elevation interference.\n\n"

        "Components with responsive elevations may encounter other components as they move between "
        "their resting elevations and dynamic elevation offsets. Because material cannot pass "
        "through other material, components avoid interfering with one another any number of ways, "
        "whether on a per component basis or using the entire app layout.\n"
        "On a component level, components can move or be removed before they cause interference. "
        "For example, a floating action button (FAB) can disappear or move off screen before a "
        "user picks up a card, or it can move if a snackbar appears.\n"
        "On the layout level, design your app layout to minimize opportunities for interference. "
        "For example, position the FAB to one side of stream of a cards so the FAB won’t interfere "
        "when a user tries to pick up one of cards.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="inbox">inbox</string>
    <string name="your_current_semester">Your Current Semester</string>
    <string name="my_four_year_plan">My Four Year Plan</string>
    <string name="dashboard_tabs">Dashboard Tabs</string>
    <string name="title_activity_home">HomeActivity</string>
    <string name="title_home">Home</string>
    <string name="title_dashboard">Dashboard</string>
    <string name="title_notifications">Notifications</string>
    <string name="planning">Planning</string>
    <string name="upcoming">Upcoming</string>
    <string name="textview">TextView</string>
    <string name="dummy_button">Dummy Button</string>
    <string name="dummy_content">DUMMY\nCONTENT</string>
    <string name="tabs">Tabs</string>
    <string name="cumulative_gpa_0_0">Cumulative GPA: 0.0</string>
    <!-- Preference Titles -->
    <string name="messages_header">Messages</string>
    <string name="sync_header">Sync</string>

    <!-- Messages Preferences -->
    <string name="signature_title">Your signature</string>
    <string name="reply_title">Default reply action</string>

    <!-- Sync Preferences -->
    <string name="sync_title">Sync email periodically</string>
    <string name="attachment_title">Download incoming attachments</string>
    <string name="attachment_summary_on">Automatically download attachments for incoming emails</string>
    <string name="attachment_summary_off">Only download attachments when manually requested</string>
    <string name="forms">Forms</string>
    <string name="cmsc_course_request_form">CMSC Course Request Form</string>
    <string name="subject_of_notification">Subject of Notification</string>
    <string name="example_body">This is where the text for the body of the notification will be shown. The text will all not show up. Only whatever fits in the container. Wher then user clicks the item, they wilj be able to see the whole thing as a dialog</string>
    <string name="textviewInbox">TextView</string>
    <string name="unread">Unread</string>
    <string name="grades">Grades</string>
    <string name="dashboardTitleTextView">Dashboard</string>
    <string name="upcomingTitle">Upcoming</string>
<<<<<<< HEAD

    <string name="ugradOverviewTitleTextView">Undergrad Program Overview</string>
    <string name="ugradStudiesSummary">
        "At the Department of Computer Science, undergraduates are a priority. Here, you will meet 3,400 (and counting)
        of the nation\'s top computer science majors. This diverse group of students has interests ranging from systems to
        programming languages, from algorithms to design and from VR to Robotics. While you are an undergraduate here,
        you will study fundamentals in computing including programming languages and theory, which will help you later in
        a variety of courses we offer at the 400-level. After taking classes, perhaps doing research, participating in our
        honors program, or studying abroad, and completing internships, our students go on to some of the best graduate programs
        in the world or join start-ups, small and large tech companies, consulting firms, or government organizations.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="ugradAdvsingTeamTextView">Undergraduate Advising Team</string>
    <string name="ugradAdvsingTeamSummaryTextView">
        "The undergraduate advising team assists with the academic and professional development of undergraduate majors and minors
        in Computer Science. We also coordinate and host myriad social, academic, and professional events including resume workshops,
        and career and internship fairs.\n\n"

        "As a student, you will interact with the undergraduate office staff during mandatory advising (which occurs once a semester)
        or whenever you would like to speak with a staff member about any issue. If you are facing academic or emotional difficulties,
        it is especially important that you contact us as soon as you are able. For general questions or concerns about the undergraduate
        program, please email us at ugrad@cs.umd.edu. We ask that you include your UID number and explain the purpose of your visit as you
        schedule your appointment; this helps us to prepare appropriately.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="advisorsTextView">Academic Advisors</string>
    <string name="courtneyTextView">
        "Courtney Cabansag\n"
        "Office: 1154 Brendan Iribe Center\n"
        "Email: cabansag@umd.edu\n\n"
        "Courtney is a Senior Academic Advisor who received her B.A. in Language, Culture &amp; Society
        from the University of California, Santa Barbara and her M.S. in Higher Postsecondary Education
        from Syracuse University. Courtney has worked in academic success, student involvement and leadership
        and most recently residence life before joining the Department of Computer Science in 2019. When she
        isn’t advising, Courtney enjoys exercising (everything from weightlifting to aerial yoga), watching
        reality television, and discovering new vegan recipes.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="brysonTextView">
        "Bryson Daniels\n"
        "Email: bdaniel7@umd.edu\n\n"
        "Bryson received his B.S. in Psychology with a Minor in Biological Sciences from Clemson University,
        and his M.Ed. in Higher Education Administration from Auburn University. Prior to joining the Computer
        Science Department, he worked within the Gossett Student-Athlete Center at the University of Maryland
        as the Interim Athletic Academic Counselor for Men's Wrestling. In his spare time, Bryson enjoys running, reading,
        and exploring the DMV area with friends and family.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="christineTextView">
        "Christine Denis\n"
        "Office: 1152 Brendan Iribe Center\n"
        "Email: cdenis@umd.edu\n\n"
        "Christine is a Senior Academic Advisor who received her B.S. in Psychology with a concentration in
        counseling at East Stroudsburg University and her M.S. in Higher Education Policy &amp; Student Affairs
        from West Chester University. Prior to joining the Computer Science Department in 2019, Christine worked
        with academic probation students and first-year Achieve! program students to cultivate academic and personal
        success at West Chester University. Christine has a special interest supporting Exploratory/Undeclared students
        in navigating indecision and declaring a major. In her free time, she enjoys traveling to the Pocono Mountains
        to visit family and friends, hiking, and spending time with her dog.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="erikTextView">
        "Erik Johanson\n"
        "Office: Brendan Iribe Center\n"
        "Email: ejohanso@umd.edu\n\n"
        "Erik received his B.S. in Biology and B.A. in History from Providence College, and his M.A. in English Literature
        from the Catholic University of America. Prior to joining the Computer Science Department, he taught literature, writing,
        and rhetoric at Catholic University and acted as a professional writing tutor at the United States Naval Academy.
        His research interests include writing pedagogy in STEM fields, best practices for university Writing Centers, and
        British Renaissance poetry. In his free time, Erik enjoys reading, writing, playing video games, and everything LEGO.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="brittanyTextView">
        "Brittany Johnson\n"
        "Office: 1150 Brendan Iribe Center\n"
        "Email: johnsobr@umd.edu\n\n"
        "Brittany is a Senior Academic Advisor for the Department of Computer Science. Brittany started her academic
        career in the Maryland Higher Education system, working at Prince George’s Community College as a testing coordinator
        while working on her undergraduate degree. She received her B.A. in English Language and Literature from the University of Maryland
        College Park in 2011. She continued her academic career as an advisor at the University of Maryland University College,
        working with the Undergraduate School to provide advising to working adults including veterans and active duty military personnel.
        She transitioned from advising to functional coordination for the implementation of a new Document Management System in the
        Office of the Registrar. She received a Graduate Certificate in Multimedia Journalism at the University of Maryland College Park
        in Spring 2019. Her research interests revolve around academic advocacy and strengthening the intersection between STEM and the
        Arts and Humanities academic fields. In her spare time, Brittany enjoys photography/videography and travel.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="natalieTextView">
        "Natalie Lightfoot-Solomon\n"
        "Office: 1148 Brendan Iribe Center\n"
        "Email: nlightfo@umd.edu\n\n"
        "Natalie is a Senior Academic Advisor who received her B.S. in Toxicology from Penn State University, her M.S.
        in Disaster Medicine and Management from Philadelphia University, and a second B.S. in Investigative Forensics
        from University of Maryland Global Campus. Natalie has worked in academic advising for over 6 years, focusing
        on problem solving and student resolutions. She is also an adjunct faculty member with University of Maryland Global Campus,
        helping new students with program and career exploration. In her spare time, Natalie loves to travel and read.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="maggieTextView">
        "Maggie Loughlin\n"
        "Email: mloughli@umd.edu\n\n"
        "Maggie is an academic advisor in the Department of Computer Science. She earned her B.A. in English Language and Literature
        at the University of Maryland in 2019, and earned her Master's Degree in Secondary Education from the University of Maryland in 2020.
        Before starting work at the University of Maryland, Maggie worked as an English Teacher in Prince George's County and as a Coordinator
        for the American Association of Colleges of Osteopathic Medicine. Her background has shaped her interest in serving students and helping
        them succeed. When she's not in the office, Maggie enjoys kayaking on the Patapsco River, playing piano, and taking long walks with her dog Bilbo.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="ashleyTextView">
        "Ashley Lyles\n"
        "Email: alyles2@umd.edu\n\n"
        "Ashley received both her B.A. in Communication Studies with minors in Spanish and French, and her M.S. in
        Higher Education Policy and Student Affairs from West Chester University. Prior to joining the Computer Science team,
        Ashley has worked in fraternity and sorority life, and most recently as an advisor to Black and Latino male students
        on an initiative to help improve the graduation and retention rates for this specific student population.
        Ashley's primary academic interests include developing support systems and equitable institutional policies for students
        of color in an effort to create a more sustainable educational experience. When she's not advising, Ashley enjoys spending
        her free time exploring new restaurants, re-watching the entire series of Grey's Anatomy, and playing with her fluffy Goldendoodle, Marco.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="larryTextView">
        "Larry Petruccy\n"
        "Email: lpetruc1@umd.edu\n\n"
        "Larry received his BA in English from St. Mary's College of Maryland. Prior to joining the Computer Science Department, Larry
        worked in K-12 education for eight years before moving on to work in higher education. During that time he worked as a high
        school English teacher and as a senior manager at a virtual school overseeing course placements for grades K-12. In higher education,
        Larry has worked with nursing students at both Walden University and Towson University in enrollment and advising roles. In his free time,
        Larry enjoys watching horror films and playing board games with family and friends.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="brennanTextView">
        "Brennan Rudy\n"
        "Email: brudy9@umd.edu\n\n"
        "Brennan received his Bachelor of Music from Susquehanna University in 2019 and his Master of Music from University of Maryland in Spring 2021.
        Prior to joining the Department of Computer Science, Brennan has worked in Residence Life, and most recently as a graduate assistant in the academic
        advising office for the Smith School of Business. In addition to advising, Brennan enjoys hiking, baking, performing in orchestras, and is currently
        pursuing a Doctor of Musical Arts at UMD.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="shreyaTextView">
        "Shreya Singh\n"
        "Email: ssingh30@umd.edu\n\n"
        "Shreya received her B.S. in Biology, Certificate in Women's Studies, and MPS in Clinical Psychology from University of Maryland.
        Prior to joining the Computer Science department, she worked with students in a living and learning program to promote research experience,
        advise students in navigating STEM coursework, and encourage community building. Shreya's academic interests involve understanding barriers
        to success faced by students of color and first generation college students. In her free time, Shreya enjoys reading, binging TV shows, and dance.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="headsOfStaffTextView">Heads of Staff</string>
    <string name="monicaTextView">
        "Monica Hilliard\n"
        "Assistant Program Director of Undergraduate Academic Affairs\n"
        "Email: monicah@umd.edu\n\n"
        "Monica received her BA in International Affairs from the University of Colorado Boulder and her MA in International Education
        from the George Washington University. Prior to joining the Department of Computer Science, she worked as Manager of Academic Records
        for the College Dean’s Office at Georgetown University. She also has several years of experience working with study abroad programs.
        In her free time, Monica enjoys exploring the outdoors, traveling, and reading.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="davidMTextView">
        "David Mount\n"
        "Associate Chair and Director of Undergraduate Studies\n"
        "Office: 5208 Brendan Iribe Center\n"
        "Email: mount@umd.edu\n\n"
        "David Mount is a professor in the Department of Computer Science at the University of Maryland with a joint appointment in the
        University's Institute for Advanced Computer Studies (UMIACS). He received his Ph.D. from Purdue University in Computer Science in 1983,
        and started at the University of Maryland in 1984. In 2001 he was a visiting professor at the Hong Kong University of Science and Technology.
        He has written over 170 research publications on algorithms for geometric problems, particularly problems with applications in image processing,
        pattern recognition, information retrieval, and computer graphics. He currently serves on the editorial boards of a number of journals,
        including ACM Transactions on Spatial Algorithms and Systems, Computational Geometry: Theory and Applications, International Journal of
        Computational Geometry &amp; Applications, and he has served on the editorial boards of ACM Trans. on Mathematical Software and Pattern Recognition.
        He was the conference chair for the 24th Annual Symposium on Computational Geometry in 2008. He has served on the program committees of many of
        the major conferences in his area, and he served as the program committee co-chair for the 19th ACM Symposium on Computational Geometry in 2003 and
        the Fourth Workshop on Algorithm Engineering and Experiments in 2002 and SPIE's Conferences on Vision Geometry from 2001 through 2006.
        He is currently serving on the Computational Geometry Steering Committee. He has won a number of awards for excellence in teaching,
        including twice winning the University of Maryland's College of Computer, Mathematical and Natural Sciences, Dean's Award for Excellence in Teaching,
        and the Award for Teaching Excellence Appreciation in 2001 at the Hong Kong University of Science and Technology. He has co-authored the textbook
        Data Structures and Algorithms in C++ with Mike Goodrich and Roberto Tamassia.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="davidTTextView">
        "David Turner\n"
        "Assistant Director of Undergraduate Studies\n"
        "Office: 1132 Brendan Iribe Center"
        "Email: dturner8@umd.edu\n\n"
        "David currently serves as the Assistant Director of Undergraduate Studies. He received his B.S. in Biological Sciences and his Ed.M. in
        Higher Education Administration both from the University at Buffalo. He joined the University of Maryland in January of 2017 as the
        Recruitment and Programming Coordinator in the Honors College. Prior to joining the University of Maryland, he worked in the Office of
        Undergraduate Admissions at West Chester University. His primary research interests are the history of higher education, accessibility of
        higher education, and accreditation and assessment. David enjoys reading, traveling, and spending time with family and friends.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="ugradPeerAdvsingTeamHeader">Undergraduate Peer Advising Team</string>
    <string name="ugradPeerAdvsingTeamSummaryTextView">
        "The Peer Advisors of the CS Undergraduate Advising Office aim to provide the best guidance for navigating the Computer Science degree and
        academic experience from the student perspective. Peer Advisors support the CS Undergraduate Advising Office in its mission to assist students
        with their academic and professional goals by being the first line of communication, triaging students’ requests, collaborating with students
        on building and editing their academic plans, directing visitors according to their needs and questions, and being otherwise prepared to provide
        general assistance to both students and advisors. To get in contact with the Peer Advisors, you are welcome to reach out via email at ugrad@cs.umd.edu
        or Instagram at @umdcs.\n\n"
    </string>
    
    <string name="mariaTextView">
        "Maria Keerthi Amala Arasu\n"
        "Peer Advisor\n\n"
        "Maria is a sophomore Computer Science major, specializing in Machine Learning, with a minor in Math. She is also an undergraduate
        TA for computer science and enjoys working with her peers. After graduating, she wants to pursue a career in Software Engineering
        and Artificial Intelligence. In her free time she enjoys traveling, listening to music, and binge-watching TV shows.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="siddheshTextView">
        "Siddhesh Gupta\n"
        "Peer Advisor\n\n"
        "Siddhesh Gupta is an International, Junior Computer Science Student from India. Siddhesh is specializing in Data Science and minoring
        in Statistics. He's also a TA for BMGT289B: How do innovators think! Siddhesy likes engaging in outside class activities.
        Currently he is the president and founder of BigTh!nk AI, a student organization at UMD. He loves to play sports and is decently good
        at 10 different sports. After graduating Siddhesh would like to work in Software Engineering field to build and innovate new software products.
        Siddhesh loves watching Formula 1 and always stay up to date with what’s new in the sport. F1 has inspired Siddhesh over the years to be innovative
        on even the smallest levels. In his free time Siddhesh likes to catch up on sleep, get involved with friends, and on-campus activities.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="surmudTextView">
        "Surmud Jamil\n"
        "Peer Advisor\n\n"
        "Surmud Jamil is from his hometown of Bel Air, Maryland, and he's a senior year computer science major. Last summer, Surmud completed a
        software engineering internship at Pearson, where he gained a lot of experience in software development. Surmud's hobbies include basketball,
        fantasy football, reading books, working out, watching netflix, and most importantly, sleeping.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="amarachiTextView">
        "Amarachi Joe-Nweke\n"
        "Peer Advisor\n\n"
        "Amarachi is a senior Computer Science major with a minor in International Development and Conflict Management. She transferred from the
        Community College of Baltimore County(CCBC) with her A.S. in Computer Science. Beyond her role as a Peer Advisor, Amarachi is also a
        leader with Bethel Campus Fellowship, a student organization on campus. When she's not studying, Amarachi enjoys cooking, watching movies,
        and spending time with family and friends.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="joshuaTextView">
        "Joshua Kalampanayil\n"
        "Peer Advisor\n\n"
        "Joshua is a second-year undergraduate student, majoring in computer science and minoring in general business and statistics.
        On campus, Joshua is also a sponsorship organizer in both Technica and Bitcamp, two hackathons run by students at the University of Maryland,
        as well as being a TA for the CS department. In his free time, Joshua loves to sleep, spend hours on TikTok, and is working toward becoming
        a game referee on the elementary school level for FIRST Robotics.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="lalithaTextView">
        "Lalitha Kasi\n"
        "Peer Advisor\n\n"
        "Lalitha is a sophomore undergraduate student majoring in Computer Science, with a specialization in cybersecurity.
        In addition to being a Peer Advisor for the Computer Science Undergraduate Advising Office, Lalitha is involved on campus as a
        I4C Teaching/Outreach Ambassador, Hospitality Chair for Maryland Masti, and a part of Technica's Finance Team. After graduation,
        she hopes to work in the field of cybersecurity intelligence. In her free time, Lalitha enjoys traveling, hiking, cooking,
        and spending quality time with her friends and family.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="katherineTextView">
        "Katherine Kim\n"
        "Peer Advisor\n\n"
        "Katherine is a junior undergraduate student double majoring in Data Science and Cell Biology and Genetics, and this is her
        first year as a peer advisor. Her overall interests include developing ethical technology, improving healthcare, and fostering education.
        Outside of school, she likes to bake/cook, exercise, spend time with friends and family, and binge watch shows. Her recent binges include
        Big Mouth, Bridgerton, Lovecraft Country, The Crown, and Rick and Morty. She prefers MCU over DCU, believes that Game of Thrones ended at season 6,
        and also watches the Bachelor (but does not recommend it to anybody because she acknowledges that 90% of it is unnecessary drama, but she
        continues to watch it anyway).\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="shivasreeTextView">
        "Shivasree Margam\n"
        "Peer Advisor\n\n"
        "Shivasree is a junior majoring in computer science with a focus in cybersecurity and minoring in innovation &amp; entrepreneurship.
        She is from Howard County, Maryland, and has moved over seven times in her life! Shivasree is a returning PA and is currently
        involved with UMD's BitView as mentor coordinator, Hindu Student Council as treasurer, and I4C as computing ambassador.
        After graduation, she aspires to use her technical and business skills to positively impact the growing society. In her free time,
        she enjoys binge-watching shows, listening to music, and spending time with friends and family.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="amodTextView">
        "Amod Mathur\n"
        "Senior Peer Advisor\n\n"
        "Amod is a student at the University of Maryland pursuing a B.S. in Computer Science with a minor in Business Analytics.
        He has been a Peer Advisor with the CS Undergraduate Advising Office since March 2020, and enjoys working with Computer Science
        students establishing their academic and professional goals. Amod plans to graduate in Spring 2022 to pursue a career in software engineering.
        On campus, Amod is involved with the QUEST Honors Program and Alpha Kappa Psi Business Fraternity. In his free time,
        Amod enjoys playing tennis and table tennis, watching Netflix, and speedsolving Rubik's Cubes.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="snehaTextView">
        "Sneha Narayanan\n"
        "Senior Peer Advisor\n\n"
        "Sneha is a third-year undergraduate student at the University of Maryland from South Brunswick, New Jersey. She is a Computer Science
        major and she is completing a minor in Business Analytics and certification in Women’s Studies. She is a peer advisor for the Department
        of Computer Science. Sneha has held various other leadership positions during her time so far at the University of Maryland including
        being an Undergraduate Computer Science Teaching Assistant, English Teaching Assistant, and helping run the Girls Who Code UMD Chapter.
        She is also involved with cultural organizations at UMD including Maryland Minza and Maryland Mauj where she is involved as a technology
        and hospitality chair. This upcoming summer she will be interning at Capital One in New York City as a Software Engineering Intern.
        Sneha really enjoys working on her interior design skills as well as working out and drinking coffee.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="kaylaTextView">
        "Kayla Norton\n"
        "Graduate Assistant\n\n"
        "Kayla is the Graduate Assistant for the CS Undergraduate Advising Office. She is pursuing her Master of Public Policy Degree,
        with a focus in health policy. Most notably, Kayla has been a member of the UMD community since 2017 - completing her undergraduate
        degree in Public Health Science May of 2020. She has a strong passion for STEM and enjoys helping Break Through Tech work to expand
        diversity in tech. In her free time, she can be found outdoors, exploring new ways to be active or grabbing coffee from a local coffee shop.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="dhvaniTextView">
        "Dhvani Patel\n"
        "Peer Advisor\n\n"
        "Dhvani is a Junior Computer Science major, with a specialization in Data Science. Along with being a Peer Advisor for the Department of
        Computer Science, she is a part-time software engineering intern at Liberty Mutual and the secretary of Alpha Omega Epsilon(a STEM based sorority).
        Some of her other hobbies include reading, dancing, and watching reality TV. A few of her favorite shows are Big Brother and Survivor but she also
        loves any crime-based show/podcast. After graduation she hopes to pursue a career in data engineering while also exploring the ethics behind AI.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="aashrayTextView">
        "Aashray Raparla\n"
        "Peer Advisor\n\n"
        "I am a junior Computer Science major with a minor in Innovation and Entrepreneurship. Outside of CS, I enjoy watching sports and playing some music.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="mansiTextView">
        "Mansi Reddy\n"
        "Peer Advisor\n\n"
        "Mansi is a senior undergraduate student from the Bay Area, California. She is majoring in Computer Science with a minor in Innovation &amp; Entrepreneurship
        and plans on working as a software engineer after graduation. On campus, Mansi is involved with the QUEST Honors Program, Technica, and is on the executive
        board of two cultural organizations Maryland Mauj and Maryland Mayuri. She also enjoys brunch, reality tv, walks, and coffee.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="ambikaTextView">
        "Ambika Sikri\n"
        "Senior Peer Advisor\n\n"
        "Ambika is a senior undergraduate student from Silver Spring, Maryland, pursuing a dual-degree in Computer Science -
        with a specialization in Data Science - and Sociology. She enjoys interacting with other students on campus as a Peer
        Advisor of the CS Undergraduate Advising Office, I4C Teaching/Outreach Ambassador, I4C Peer Mentor Ambassador, and Honors Ambassador.
        Ambika also serves as Vice President on the establishing board of the Leading Women of Tomorrow chapter at UMD and is involved
        with other organizations on campus. After graduation, she hopes to work in a space that advances tech innovation for social good.
        Ambika's favorite times are those spent with her friends &amp; family, but she's also almost always listening to music and loves trying
        different creative projects, reading, or watching Netflix.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="nandiniTextView">
        "Nandini Venkatesh\n"
        "Peer Advisor\n\n"
        "Nandini is a junior from New Jersey and is majoring in Computer Science (General Track) and Economics. She is also an undergraduate
        TA for CMSC330 and a Computing Ambassador for I4C. After graduation she hopes to pursue a career in Software Engineering and Software
        Development. Some of her hobbies include singing, watching Netflix, and spending time with friends and family.\n\n"
    </string>
=======
    <string name="mathRequirements"><font size="15"><b>Required Lower Level Coursework</b></font>\n\n
        <i>Math Requirements</i>:\n\n
<li>MATH140 (4) Calculus 1</li>\n
<li>MATH141 (4) Calculus 2</li>\n
<li>STAT4XX (3) Must have a prerequisite of MATH141; Cannot be cross listed with CMSC</li>\n
<li>MATH/STATXXX (3/4) Must have a prerequisite of MATH141; Cannot be cross listed with CMSC</li>\n\n

*Data Science and Machine Learning Students must take MATH240 (4) Linear Algebra</string>
    <string name="csRequirements"><i>Computer Science Requirements</i>:\n\n
    <li>CMSC131 (4) Object-Oriented Programming I* OR CMSC133 (2) Object-Oriented Programming I Beyond Fun</li>\n
    <li>CMSC132 (4) Object-Oriented Programming II</li>\n
    <li>CMSC216 (4) introduction to Computer Systems*</li>\n
    <li>CMSC250 (4) Discrete Structures*</li>\n
    <li>CMSC330 (3) Organizations of Programming Languages</li>\n
    <li>CMSC351 (3) Algorithms</li>\n
    *An exemption exam is available for this course
    </string>
    <string name="upperLevel"><font size="15"><b>Upper Level Concentration:</b></font>\n\n
    All students, regardless of specialization, must complete 12 credit hours of 300 - 400 level courses in one discipline outside of Computer Science with a cumulative GPA of 1.7 or higher in this coursework. No course that is in, or crosslisted as, CMSC may be counted in this requirement (e.g., AMSC460). Only 1 independent study or experiential learning course may be used. Students who are pursuing a minor or a double major/dual degree may use those credits in this area with the exception of a few majors/disciplines (e.g., Information Science). Please consult with your advisor to ensure the courses you plan to take to ensure they will satisfy this requirement.\n</string>
    <string name="LEP"><font size="15"><b>Limited Enrollment Program (LEP) Benchmarks*</b></font>\n\n
    * These benchmarks apply to new freshman (matriculated Fall 2019 and later), new transfer students, and internal transfers changing majors within the University *\n\n
    All students will undergo a benchmark review at 45 and 75 credits. Students in the major are required to complete the following courses:
    <font size="13"><b><i>45-Credit Benchmark Requirements</i></b></font>\n
        <li>Completion of CMSC 131 with a minimum grade of C-</li>\n
        <li>Completion of CMSC 132 with a minimum grade of C-</li>\n
        <li>Completion of MATH 140 with a minimum grade of C-</li>\n
        <li>A minimum grade point average of 2.0 in all courses taken at the University of Maryland and all other institutions</li>\n\n
    <font size="13"><b><i>75-Credit Benchmark Requirements</i></b></font>\n
        <li>Completion of CMSC 330 with a minimum grade of C-</li>\n
        <li>Completion of CMSC 351 with a minimum grade of C-</li>\n
        <li>Completion of a STAT4XX course (prerequisite: MATH141) with a minimum grade of C- or MATH/AMSC/STAT course (prerequisite: MATH141) with a minimum grade of C-</li>\n
        <li>A minimum grade point average of 2.0 in all courses taken at the University of Maryland and all other institutions</li>\n
    </string>
    <string name="degReqs"><font size="15"><b>Degree Requirements:</b></font>\n\n
    Students within the Computer Science major may choose to pursue our General Track or one of three specializations offered. Students are not required to pursue a specialization but may find one best fits their interests. Students interested in declaring a specialization should speak with their assigned academic advisor.\n\n
    Students, regardless of specialization, are required to fulfill their computer science upper level course requirements from at least 3 areas. Courses that fall within each area are listed in the General Track degree requirements. The five areas are:\n Area 1: Systems\n Area 2: Information Processing\n Area 3: Software Engineering and Programming Languages\n Area 4: Theory\n Area 5: Numerical Analysis\n\n
    For tracks requiring CMSC electives, three 1-credit CMSC STIC courses are equivalent to one 3-credit 300-400 level elective course. Visit UMD\'s official STICs website and our FAQ page for more information on STICs and see your assigned advisor for information on how STICs can fit into your specialization.\n</string>
    <string name="areas">\nAt the upper level, students take five (5) CMSC 400 level courses from at least three different areas (see below) with no more than three courses in a given area. An additional two (2) CMSC electives, totaling 6 credits, are also required. If students take more than three courses from an area, the additional course(s) will be counted as upper level computer science electives.\n\n
    <b>Area 1: Systems</b>\n
    <li>CMSC 411 (3) Computer Systems Architecture\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 412 (4) Operating Systems *\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 414 (3) Computer and Network Security\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 416 (3) Introduction to Parallel Computing\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 417 (3) Computer Networks\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 498X (3) Selected Topics in Computer Science; Introduction to Software-defined Radio and Wireless Communications (course will fulfill requirement for students who are enrolled the course in Fall 2018 or Fall 2019 semester *only*) or\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 498X* (3) Selected Topics in Computer Science; Introduction to Parallel Computing (course will fulfill requirement for students who are enrolled the course in Fall 2020 semester *only*)\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 498K* (3) Big Data Systems (course will fulfill requirement for students who are enrolled in the course in Spring 2018 or Spring 2019 *only*)\n\n</li>
    Students may not receive credit for both iterations of CMSC 498X at this time.\n\n

    <b>Area 2: Information Processing</b>\n
    <li>CMSC 420 (3) Data Structures\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 421 (3) Introduction to Artificial Intelligence\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 422 (3) Machine Learning *\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 423 (3) Bioinformatic Algorithms, Databases, and Tools\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 424 (3) Database Design\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 426 (3) Computer Vision *\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 427 (3) Computer Graphics *\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 470 (3) Introduction to Natural Language Processing *\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 471 (3) Introduction to Data Visualization (Area 2 OR Area 3)\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 498F (3) Selected Topics in Computer Science; Advances in XR (course will fulfill requirement for students who are enrolled the course in Spring 2022 semester *only*)\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 498V (3) Advanced Topics in Machine Learning (course will fulfill requirement students who are enrolled in the course in Fall 2018 *only*)\n\n</li>

    <b>Area 3: Software Engineering and Programming Languages</b>\n
    <li>CMSC 430 (3) Introduction to Compilers\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 433 (3) Programming Language Technologies and Paradigms\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 434 (3) Introduction to Human-Computer Interaction\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 435 (3) Software Engineering *\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 436 (3) Hand Held Programming Devices\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 471 (3) Introduction to Data Visualization (Area 2 OR Area 3)\n\n</li>

    <b>Area 4: Theory</b>\n
    <li>CMSC 451 (3) Design and Analysis of Computer Algorithms\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 452 (3) Elementary Theory of Computation\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 454 (3) Algorithms for Data Science\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 456 (3) Cryptology *\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 457 (3) Introduction to Quantum Computing\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 474 (3) Introduction to Computational Game Theory\n\n</li>

    <b>Area 5: Numerical Analysis (choose one)</b>\n
    <li>CMSC 460 (3) Computational Methods (credit will only be given for CMSC 460 or CMSC 466) *\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 466 (3) Introduction to Numerical Analysis (credit will only be given for CMSC 466 or CMSC 460) *\n\n</li>

    <b>CMSC Upper Level Electives</b>\n
    These courses do not count toward a distributive area for the General Track. If you have any questions about what courses will satisfy distributive area requirements, consult with your assigned academic advisor.\n/n
    <li>CMSC 320 (3) Introduction to Data Science\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 335 (3) Web Application Development with JavaScript (formerly CMSC398N)\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 388 or 389 (1) Student Initiated Courses (STICs)\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 389N (3) Special Topics in Computer Science; Introduction to PHP &amp; JavaScript\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 425 (3) Game Programming *\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 472 (3) Introduction to Deep Learning *\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 473 (3) Capstone in Machine Learning *\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 475 (3) Combinatorics and Game Theory *\n</li>
    <li>CMSC498 (1 - 3) Special Topics in Computer Science courses not otherwise listed in a distributive area\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 498A (1 - 3) Selected Topics in Computer Science: Independent Study\n</li>
    <li>CMSC 499A (1 - 3) Independent Undergraduate Research\n\n</li>

    * Indicates this course has unique prerequisites.</string>
    <string name="cyberText">\nStudents looking to pursue the cybersecurity specialization are required to complete the lower level courses (MATH140, MATH141, CMSC131, CMSC132, CMSC216, CMSC250), the additional required courses (CMSC330, CMSC351, MATH/STATXXX and STAT4xx beyond MATH141), and the upper level concentration. The difference in the specialization is the upper level computer science courses.\n
Students must fulfill their computer science upper level course requirements from at least 3 areas. Students may fulfill an area requirement under the Upper Level Elective Courses requirement. Courses that fall within each area are listed in the CS Distributive Areas and Electives document.\n\n
    <b>Required:\n</b>
    <li>CMSC 414 (3) Computer and Network Security</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 456 (3) Cryptology *</li>\n\n
    <b>Choose 4 courses from:\n</b>
    <li>CMSC 411 (3) Computer Systems Architecture</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 412 (4) Operating Systems *</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 417 (3) Computer Networks</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 430 (3) Introduction to Compilers</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 433 (3) Programming Language Technologies and Paradigms</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 451 (3) Design and Analysis of Computer Algorithms</li>\n\n
    <b>Upper Level Elective Courses\n</b>
    Students must select 3 credits from CMSC 300- or 400-level coursework (not eligible, CMSC330 and CMSC351)\n\n
    * Indicates this course has unique prerequisites.</string>
    <string name="dsText">\nStudents looking to pursue the data science specialization are required to complete the lower level courses (MATH140, MATH141, CMSC131, CMSC132, CMSC216, CMSC250), the additional required courses (CMSC330, CMSC351, STAT400 and MATH240), and the upper level concentration requirements. The difference in the specialization is the upper level computer science courses.\n
Students must fulfill their computer science upper level course requirements from at least 3 areas. Students may fulfill an area requirement under the Upper Level Elective Courses requirement. Courses that fall within each area are listed in the CS Distributive Areas and Electives document.\n\n
    <b>Required:\n</b>
    <li>MATH 240 (4) Linear Algebra</li>\n
    <li>STAT 400 (3) Applied Probability and Statistics I</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 320 (3) Introduction to Data Science</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 422 (3) Introduction to Machine Learning *</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 424 (3) Database Design</li>\n\n
    <b>Choose 1 course from:</b>\n
    <li>CMSC 402 (3) Bioinformatic Algorithms &amp; Methods for Functional Genomics and Proteomics</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 420 (3) Data Structures</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 421 (3) Introduction to Artificial Intelligence</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 423 (3) Bioinformatic Algorithms, Databases, and Tools</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 425 (3) Game Programming *</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 426 (3) Computer Vision</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 427 (3) Computer Graphics *</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 470 (4) Natural Language Processing *</li>\n\n
    <b>Choose 1 course from:\n</b>
    <li>CMSC 451 (3) Design and Analysis of Computer Algorithms</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 454 (3) Algorithms for Data Science</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 460 (3) Computational Methods</li>\n\n
    <b>Choose 2 courses from:\n</b>
    <li>CMSC 411 (3) Computer Systems Architecture</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 412 (4) Operating Systems *</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 414 (3) Computer and Network Security</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 417 (3) Computer Networks</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 430 (3) Introduction to Compilers</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 433 (3) Programming Language Technologies and Paradigms</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 434 (3) Introduction to Human-Computer Interaction</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 435 (3) Software Engineering *</li>\n\n
    * Indicates this course has unique prerequisites.</string>
    <string name="qiText">\nStudents looking to pursue the quantum information specialization are required to complete the lower level courses (MATH140, MATH141, CMSC131, CMSC132, CMSC216, CMSC250), the additional required courses (CMSC330, CMSC351, STAT4xx with a MATH141 prerequisite, and MATH240), and the upper level concentration requirements. The difference in the specialization is the upper level computer science courses. Students must fulfill their computer science upper level course requirements from at least 3 areas.\n\n
Students must fulfill their computer science upper level course requirements from at least 3 areas. Students may fulfill an area requirement under the Upper Level Elective Courses requirement. Courses that fall within each area are listed in the CS Distributive Areas and Electives document.\n\n
    <b>Required:\n</b>
    <li>MATH 240 (4) Linear Algebra</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 457 (3) Introduction to Quantum Computing *</li>\n
    <li>PHYS 467 (3) Introduction to Quantum Technology *</li>\n\n
    <b>Choose 4 courses from:\n</b>
    <li>CMSC 411 (3) Computer Systems Architecture</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 412 (4) Operating Systems *</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 417 (3) Computer Networks</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 430 (3) Introduction to Compilers</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 433 (3) Programming Language Technologies and Paradigms</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 451 (3) Design and Analysis of Computer Algorithms</li>\n\n
    <b>Upper Level Elective Courses</b>\n
    Students must select 3 credits from CMSC 300- or 400-level coursework (not eligible, CMSC330 and CMSC351)\n\n
    * Indicates this course has unique prerequisites.</string>
    <string name="mlText">\nStudents looking to pursue the machine learning specialization are required to complete the lower level courses (MATH140, MATH141, CMSC131, CMSC132, CMSC216, CMSC250), the additional required courses (CMSC330, CMSC351, STAT4xx with a MATH141 prerequisite, and MATH240), and the upper level concentration requirements. The difference in the specialization is the upper level computer science courses. Students must fulfill their computer science upper level course requirements from at least 3 areas.\n
Students must fulfill their computer science upper level course requirements from at least 3 areas. Students may fulfill an area requirement under the Upper Level Elective Courses requirement. Courses that fall within each area are listed in the CS Distributive Areas and Electives document.\n\n
    <b>Required:\n</b>
    <li>MATH 240 (4) Linear Algebra</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 320 (3) Introduction to Data Science</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 421 (3) Introduction to Artificial Intelligence</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 422 (3) Introduction to Machine Learning *</li>\n\n
    <b>Choose 2 courses from:\n</b>
    <li>CMSC 426 (3) Computer Vision *</li>\n
    <li>CMSC/AMSC 460 (3) Computational Methods * <b>or</b> CMSC/AMSC 466 (3) Introduction to Numerical Analysis I * <b>or</b> MATH 401 (3) Applications of Linear Algebra *</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 470 (3) Natural Language Processing *</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 472 (3) Introduction to Deep Learning (formerly CMSC 498L)</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 473 (3) Capstone in Machine Learning (formerly CMSC 498P)</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 474 (3) Introduction to Computational Game Theory</li>\n
    <li>CMSC 476 (3) Robotics and Perception</li>\n\n
    <b>Upper Level Elective Courses</b>\n
    Six credits from CMSC3XX or CMSC4XX excluding CMSC330 and CMSC351\n\n
    * Indicates this course has unique prerequisites.</string>

>>>>>>> cdb381d12437207a3f2d362d3376684fb9c6e783
</resources>